<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education Funding UK</title>
    <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Education Funding UK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://educationfunding.uk/funding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>14-16 Funding</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/14-16-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/14-16-funding/</guid>
      <description>Colleges are able to claim direct funding for learners who are aged 14 or 15 on 31st August if they are studying full time with the provider.
There are additional requirements and responsibilities for this sort of provision, and although the national curriuculum does not have to be delivered, it does need to be &amp;lsquo;broad and balanced&amp;rsquo;, covering essentials like English, Maths, and Science, as well as religious education and relationships / sex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adult Education Budget</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/adult-education-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/adult-education-budget/</guid>
      <description>The Adult Education Budget is split into two funding methods: Adult Skills and Community Learning.
Adult Skills is qualification-based funding that depends on the size and type of qualification being studied (as well a number of eligibility requirements for the learner).
Community Learning is a fixed allocation that can be spent by training providers in the education and support of disadvantaged learners, or in subject areas not covered by regulated qualifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apprenticeship Funding</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/apprenticeship-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/apprenticeship-funding/</guid>
      <description>Each apprenticeship standard constitutes a specification for training in a particular industry and role, which should help prepare learners for employment in that area. These standards are assigned funding caps, which represents the maximum amount of money that the ESFA will release via funding.
Training providers are able to agree an overall cost (the Total Negotiated Price or TNP) with employers. The TNP can exceed the funding cap, but the employer must pay this excess themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Higher Education Funding</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/higher-education-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/higher-education-funding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Higher Technical Qualification Funding</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/higher-technical-qualification-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/higher-technical-qualification-funding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiply Funding</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/multiply-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/multiply-funding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sector-based Work Academy Programmes (SWAPs)</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/swap-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/swap-funding/</guid>
      <description>Technically part of the Adult Education Budget, these are bundles of training and work experiences that lead to a guaranteed interview (although not necessarily a job!) with a local employer.
Learners must be in receipt of JSA, ESA, or Universal Credit, and must be referred by the DWP (i.e. a local Job Centre). There is some flexibility for the training provider to proactively recruit eligible learners and get the DWP to retrospectively make a referral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills Bootcamp Funding</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/skills-bootcamp-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/skills-bootcamp-funding/</guid>
      <description>Skills Bootcamps offer free, flexible courses of up to 16 weeks. They are available for adults aged 19 or over who are either in work or recently unemployed and live in England. Some Skills Bootcamps have additional eligibility criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supported Internships</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/supported-internships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/supported-internships/</guid>
      <description>Supported Internships (SIs) are a work-based study programme for 16 to 24 year olds with SEND who have an education health and care (EHC) plan, who want to move into employment and who need extra support to do so. SIs are designed to equip young people with the skills they need to secure and sustain employment through learning in the workplace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T Level Funding</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/t-level-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/t-level-funding/</guid>
      <description>T Levels are a new type of vocational training programme, designed to occupy the space between A Levels and Apprenticeships.
They are focused on providing core technical skills alongside comprehensive work experience, tailored to specific job roles (in this regard they work alongside the new apprenticeship standards).
T Levels require two years to complete, and must include a nine-week industry placement (315 hours total).
Just like 16-19 study programmes they are funded based on the number of planned hours, but use an extended version of the funding bands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traineeship Funding</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/traineeship-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/traineeship-funding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young Person Programme Funding</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/young-person-programme-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/funding/young-person-programme-funding/</guid>
      <description>This is funding aimed at learners aged 16-18 (or 19-24 with an EHCP).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
