<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Education Funding UK</title>
    <link>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Education Funding UK</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://educationfunding.uk/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Latest News (August 2023)</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/202308-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/202308-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I updated this site, but a lot has happened and a new (academic) year has begun, so an update seemed in order!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Firstly, you may have noticed that the front page now offers different sections for different nations, and this is further broken down by type of training provider - this is to address the longstanding emphasis on Further Education in England, despite the website aspiring to provide resources for all education across all of the UK. More work will be done in the future on rounding out our support for Northern Ireland, Scotland, and Wales.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the National Skills Fund?</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/what-is-the-national-skills-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/what-is-the-national-skills-fund/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Skills Fund is a new funding option within the Adult Education Budget, which offers learners aged 19+ the opportunity to claim full funding for their first full level 3 qualification. Unlike the Level 3 Legal Entitlement, there is no upper age limit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only a targeted selection of qualifications fall into the NSF, these are aims that the ESFA believes will ‘&amp;hellip;help adults to train and gain the valuable skills they need to improve their job prospects. It will support the immediate economic recovery and future skills needs by boosting the supply of skills that employers require’ (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/guidance/national-skills-fund)&#34;&gt;https://www.gov.uk/guidance/national-skills-fund)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Does Apprenticeship Funding Work?</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/how-does-apprenticeship-funding-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/how-does-apprenticeship-funding-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh boy, apprenticeship funding is confusing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the basic idea, which I stole from the technical funding guide that the ESFA published.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-scenario&#34;&gt;The scenario&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine we have a &lt;strong&gt;12 month&lt;/strong&gt; apprenticeship with a funding cap of &lt;strong&gt;£12,000&lt;/strong&gt;. That cap is there because the ESFA don&amp;rsquo;t think it should cost any more than that to deliver the apprenticeship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The training provider agrees a TNP (Total Negotiated Price) of &lt;strong&gt;£15,000&lt;/strong&gt; with the employer because&amp;hellip; well sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s the way things go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latest News (July 2021)</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/202107-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/202107-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welp, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Life has been a tad busy, so I&amp;rsquo;ve not been able to keep on top of this as much as I would have liked to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve redesigned the appearance a little, hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s easy on the eyes. I&amp;rsquo;ve also adjusted the main page so that it provides quick links to the main funding areas - I might keep working on this depending on how well it works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latest News (March 2021)</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/202103-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/202103-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello again!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new site has been running for a few weeks now, and feedback has been good about the core concept and functionality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some users rightly pointed out that the design was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?&amp;amp;q=what+is+plagiarism&#34;&gt;too close&lt;/a&gt; to that used for official government services, and despite the disclaimers dotted around the site, was liable to cause confusion and mislead people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was certainly not my intention - rather I wanted to provide a seamless experience when navigating between different resources - but I can see that it was a little too close for comfort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Find Qualifications</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/how-to-find-qualifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/how-to-find-qualifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a few different online services that you can use to search for qualifications, find out whether they are eligible for ESFA funding, and connect with awarding bodies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One quick way to search for these from the front page of &lt;a href=&#34;https://educationfunding.uk/&#34;&gt;EducationFunding.UK&lt;/a&gt; is to type &lt;span class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;fqs&lt;/span&gt; - this is a shortcode for &amp;lsquo;find qualification services&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-a-learning-aim&#34;&gt;Find a Learning Aim&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a new government service which you can use to search for qualifications via their name or aim reference - in addition you can also filter results by level and awarding body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://educationfunding.uk/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, this is a quick post to say hello!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After working in the field of education funding for several years, I have amassed a prodigious list of bookmarks - and every year the list grows as more resources are published, new organisations emerge, and new web services are developed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was becoming tricky to keep track of all these links, and trickier still to make them available to colleagues in a simple and straightforward way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
